KARTIK SHAH

kartik.isworking@gmail.com | +91 987 065 9145 | Mumbai

https://github.com/ikartiks | https://in.linkedin.com/in/ikartiks | http://stackoverflow.com/users/1826559/kartik-shah

Summary of Experience

I have 6.3 years of experience in various domains like Banking, digital marketing & healthcare. My core forte is Android, but I have worked on both frontend and backend using technologies like Angular JS, Spring & Hibernate. I have also worked on NoSql technologies like CouchDb which offers in built sync mechanism with conflict resolution. I provide end to end Omni channel experience to clients as per requirements. I like building products. Love to teach & learn. This is a std. 1 page resume, detailed available on demand. Looking for an opportunity at New South Wales, Australia (state sponsored PR holder, can shift ASAP).

Education

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology, Mumbai University, 2011

Certifications

Google & Udacity's Android Developer Nanodegree Udacity's Self Driving Car Nanodegree (Ongoing)

Technical Skills

Strong: Android, Kotlin, Backbase, CouchDB, Building voice actions with Home

Knowledgeable: Angular JS, Spring, JPA, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, SQL, Oracle, Python, Machine Learning, core PHP

Methodology: Agile using Jira & Pivotal Tracker, SCRUM.

Tools: Jenkins for Continues integration, Burp Suite for network security, J-meter for load testing, GIT for version control.

Work Experience

OCT 2015 - OCT 2018, Tata Consultancy Services. IT Analyst, Mumbai

- Leading a team of 7 developers to build a Banking application (HDFC). App has 10M+ installs & 3.4 * rating.
- Built a hybrid app using phonegap for Sony Picture Entertainment's Digital windows project.
- Built, developed websites (backend and frontend) for Sony Picture Entertainment's SmartR project, SOAR

Mar 2015 - Oct 2015, Freestone InfoTech Pvt. Ltd. Developer, Mumbai

- Led & performed development & maintenance using server side using Spring, JPA, and Hibernate.
- Managed complete lifecycle of app Vee Smart Home (VSH).

Mar 2014 - Nov 2014, Gray Matrix Developer, Mumbai

- Led the development 3 projects Team Tracker, Cakesanpp and Dr. Fixit.
- Team Tracker was a product that helped us gain many customers as company's first product.

May 2013 - Mar 2014, Megasys India Developer, Mumbai

Built, developed & designed complete lifecycle of 'IMSafe' mobile app, which was appreciated across states and within the
media as well.

Feb 2012 - May 2013, Experience Commerce Pvt. Ltd. Developer, Mumbai

 Built & developed apps for engaging brands like Britannia, IPL Team - Royal Challengers Bangalore, United Spirits Limited, Adlabs Imagica and Daily News Analysis (DNA) newspaper.

Major Projects

HDFC Bank	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hdfc.retail.banking&hl=en	Android, Backbase
GRE Flashcards & Tests (My product)	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kartik.grevocab	Android, Kotlin
SPE – SmartR, Digital		Spring, Hibernate JPA,
Windows		AngularJS, Phonegap
EPMWare	http://epmware.com/	
Home Automation		Android, PHP
арр		
Dr. Fixit	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pidilite.drfixit	Hybrid app development
Team Tracker	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.graymatrix.teamtracker	Android, Couch database
ImSafe		Android
USL's RCB IPL Team	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.royalchallengers.android	Android, core JS, PHP
USL's Signature	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.usl.signatureselfies	Android, core JS, PHP
Selfies app		
Britania's iHealthU	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ihealthu.program.challenge	Android, core JS, PHP
Adlabs Imagica	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.adlabs.themepark	Android, core JS, PHP
Castrol Cricket	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.castrolcricket.android	Android, core JS, PHP
EC Diwali cracker app	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.experiencecommerce.android	Android, core JS, PHP

Awards & Leadership

- Best team award at TCS, Client appreciation across multiple projects.
- Complete sponsorship to Mobile developer summit held in Bangalore 2013.
- Complete sponsorship to Udacity & Google's Android Developer Nanodegree course.
- Complete sponsorship to Google's Android Career summit Bangalore 2016 for top 50 selected Android developers across India.
- Conducted multiple trainings in JAVA, Android & JavaScript at TCS, single training on Machine Learning.